Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Bruchstücke aus den Memoirien eines Tonkünstlers: Freie Fantasie für Piano Solo: [in C major], October 1, 1884; 13 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 11)
  Date of composition at end: 10/27/1884.
- Autumn Leaves Album: [for] Piano, March 12, 1870; 52 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 12)
  The number "11" written in pencil on caption. In 2 books. Contents: [bk.1]. 1. Twighlight; 2. Der Hausfrieden; 3. Mystyfied; 4. Ein Kobold; 5. Am Herde Sitzend; 6. Auf dem Wege nach dem Walde; 7. The violet; 8. Der Bettler; 9. Auf der Wiese -- bk.2. 10. Der Zigeuner im Walde; 11. Die Mutter an der Wiege; 12. An der Mühle; 13. Das Fischlein im Bache; 14. Der Mönch im Kloster; 15. Auf dem Lande; 16. Die Erzählung; 17. Fange mich; 18. In der Nacht; 19. Immer lustig; 20. Die Spinnerin; 21. Die Kapelle im Dorfe; 22. Der Waltzer im Traum; 23. Herzens Güte; 24. Scherzo-serioso [revised December 6th, 1902, Pittsburgh, Pa.]. Location: New York.
- Polka de Concert: La Comtesse: for Piano: [in Db major], 6 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 13)
- The Gypsy: Morceau Characteristique: for Piano: [in C major], 5 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 14)
  The number "10" penciled in on t.p.
- Gavotte: [no.] 27: Cara Mio: for Piano: [in Bb major], 4 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 15)
  The number "27" written in pencil on t.p. Small score (28 cm.). Picture of young child with butterfly net pasted in on top left corner.
- 3d Ward Public School March: [in F major]: [for piano], December 26, 1882; 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 16)
  At head of title: No. 2. On t.p.: Dedicated to Superintendent Lucky.
- Romance: in Eb Major: für Octett Blassinstrumente Bestimt, July 11, 1885; 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 17)
  "Score piano" on t.p. Is this an arrangement of a wind piece for solo piano? On cover and t.p.: Meinem Freunde. Francis H. Diller. freundlichst gewidmet.
- Leb Wohl mein Ideal: Characterstück: [for] Piano: [in Ab major], March 27, 1878; 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 18)
- Wait for me, Vernon: Polka for the Piano: [in Db major], February 19, 1875; 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 19)
  "Opus 113" written in red ink on t.p. At head of title: Dedicated to my friend andstudent [illegible] Vernon Fahnestock (?) of Pittsburgh, Pa.
- Fantasie Moderne: for Piano solo: [in Bb major], January 11, 1885; 11 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 20)
  Date of composition at end: 1/14/1885.
- Polka de La Reine: pour le Piano: [in E major], August 29, 1883; 6 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 21)
  On t.p. the "gn" in "Reign" is crossed off and replaced with "ne." On the caption, it is spelled "Reign." Date of composition at end: 9/5/1883.
- To the Memory of Maud Holtzman: Noturno: in Ab Major: for Piano solo, February 18, 1892; 4 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 22)
  The number "2" is penciled in on t.p. On verso of t.p. is a poem by Zitterbart pasted in.
- 4tes Concerto Militaire: in E Minor: for Violin and Piano, April 22, 1887?; 1 score (22 p.), and violin part (9 p.) (Box 66, Folder 23)
  Date of composition almost illegible. The "4tes" in title written in pencil on t.p. A picture of soldier is pasted in on t.p.
  - 4tes Concerto Militaire - Score, April 22, 1887?; 1.
  - 4tes Concerto Militaire - Parts: Violin, April 22, 1887?; 2.
- The Spectre: Tarantella: No. 3: in D Minor: for Piano solo, April 22, 1891; 8 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 24)
  The number "14" penciled in on t.p. The number "11" written in red ink on t.p. Hand drawn illustration of a witch and demons roasting a pot over a fire pit pasted in on t.p.
- Southern Sketch: [for] Piano: [in Eb major], 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 25)
  The number "18" penciled in on t.p At head of title: To Miss Adalaid Zitterbart. An insertion of 1 measure in red ink is on p. 2.
- La Petit Tarantella: No. 1: in G Major: for Piano, 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 26)
  The number "15" penciled in on t.p
- La Petit Tarantella: No. 2: in D Major: for Piano, 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 27)
  The number "16" penciled in on t.p
- La Petit Tarantella: No. 3: in D Minor: for Piano, 3 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 28)
  The number "17" penciled in on t.p Additional title on caption: The geni.
- The Puerto Rico Tarantella: for Piano: [in Bb major], August 5, 1888; 7 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 29)
  The number "13" penciled in on t.p
- A Ladys Musical Album: for the Pianoforte, 1867; 2 p. of music (Box 66, Folder 30)
  Incomplete. Only 1st page. No. 1, Larghetto (Sehnsucht). Follows the Lied ohne Worte. Location: New York.
- Fantasy Rural: in D Major: for Violin, Flute, Viola, and Piano, November 30, 1904; 1 score (28 p.), flute part (4 p. ), violin part (5 p.), and viola part (4 p.) (Box 66, Folder 31)
  On cover, "Lay usefulness, that rustic virtues by. To manly confidence thy thought apply (Dryden)." There is a final movement titled "Good night." Contents: 1. The forge: Moderato -- 2. Anita, the blacksmiths daughter: Allegretto -- 3. The ride through the woods: Allegro con moto -- 4. Finale. The country dance at the inn.
  - Fantasy Rural - Score, November 30, 1904; 1.
  - Fantasy Rural - Parts: Flute, November 30, 1904; 2.
  - Fantasy Rural - Parts: Violin, November 30, 1904; 3.
  - Fantasy Rural - Parts: Viola, November 30, 1904; 4.
- Fantasy Romantique: in E Minor: for 2 Flutes (or violins), Viola and Piano, July 11, 1904; 1 score (39 p.), flute 1 (or violin 1) part (6 p.), flute 2 (or violin 2) part (6 p.), and viola part (7 p.) (Box 66, Folder 32)
  The number "4" pasted on t.p Illustration of mother and daughter by the lake pasted in on cover.
  - Fantasy Romantique - Score, July 11, 1904; 1.
  - Fantasy Romantique - Parts: Flute 1 (or Violin 1), July 11, 1904; 2.
  - Fantasy Romantique - Parts: Flute 2 (or Violin 2), July 11, 1904; 3.
  - Fantasy Romantique - Parts: Viola, July 11, 1904; 4.
- Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1: for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello: [in A major], October 3, 1914; 1 score (29 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 67, Folder 1)
  The number "1" written in pencil on t.p. Score is written in pencil.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1 - Score, October 3, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1 - Parts: Violin 1, October 3, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1 - Parts: Violin 2, October 3, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1 - Parts: Viola, October 3, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 1 - Parts: Violoncello, October 3, 1914; 5.
- Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2: [for string quartett: in C major], October 22, 1914; 1 score (25 p.), violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 67, Folder 2)
  The number "2" pasted in on parts. Score is written in pencil, with "2nd book" above title.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2 - Score, October 22, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 1, October 22, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 2, October 22, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2 - Parts: Viola, October 22, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violoncello, October 22, 1914; 5.
- Chips of Fantasy: No. 3: [for string quartett: in C major], October 27, 1914; 1 score (24 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 67, Folder 3)
  The number "3" pasted in on parts. Score is written in pencil, with "III" above title.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 3 - Score, October 27, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 3 - Parts: Violin 1, October 27, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 3 - Parts: Violin 2, October 27, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 3 - Parts: Viola, October 27, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 3 - Parts: Violoncello, October 27, 1914; 5.
- Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4: [for string quartett: in D major], November 1, 1914; 1 score (19 p.), violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 67, Folder 4)
  The number "4" pasted in on parts.Score is written in pencil, with corrections throughout. The 1st and 3rd movements are written on half sheets attached to the score.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4 - Score, November 1, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4 - Parts: Violin 1, November 1, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4 - Parts: Violin 2, November 1, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4 - Parts: Viola, November 1, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no]. 4 - Parts: Violoncello, November 1, 1914; 5.
- Chips of Fantasy: No. 5: [for string quartett: in D minor], November 6, 1914; violin 1 part (8 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 67, Folder 5)
  The number "5" pasted in on parts. The number "494" penciled in t.p.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 5 - Parts: Violin 1, November 6, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 5 - Parts: Violin 2, November 6, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 5 - Parts: Viola, November 6, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 5 - Parts: Violoncello, November 6, 1914; 4.
- Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6: for String Quartett: [in C major], November 21, 1914; 1 score (28 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (7 p.), viola part (7 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 67, Folder 6)
  The number "6" written in black ink on wrapper for parts and on parts. The Roman number "VI" on wrapper for parts and on cover of score. The number "491" written in pencil on parts warpper. The number "493" written on cover of score. on top of second cover. Score is written in pencil.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6 - Score, November 21, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6 - Parts: Violin 1, November 21, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6 - Parts: Violin 2, November 21, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6 - Parts: Viola, November 21, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 6 - Parts: Violoncello, November 21, 1914; 5.
- Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7: for String Quartett: [in F major], November 30, 1914; 1 score (24 p.), violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (5 p.) (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7 - Score, November 30, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7 - Parts: Violin 1, November 30, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7 - Parts: Violin 2, November 30, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7 - Parts: Viola, November 30, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: [no.] 7 - Parts: Violoncello, November 30, 1914; 5.
    The number "492" penciled in on cover of score. The number "7" pasted in on parts. Score written in pencil.
- Chips of Fantasy: No. 8: for String Quartett: [in Eb major], December 9, 1914; 1 score (22 p.), violin 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), viola part (5 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 67, Folder 8)
  The number "8" pasted in on parts. Score written in pencil.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 8 - Score, December 9, 1914; 1.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 8 - Parts: Violin 1, December 9, 1914; 2.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 8 - Parts: Violin 2, December 9, 1914; 3.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 8 - Parts: Viola, December 9, 1914; 4.
  - Chips of Fantasy: No. 8 - Parts: Violoncello, December 9, 1914; 5.
- Entre-act: Fantastiqué: for Violin, Viola, Violoncello and Piano, March 15, 1875; piano part (12 p.), violin part (4 p.), viola part (4 p.), and violoncello part (4 p.) (Box 67, Folder 9)
  The number "1" pasted in on cover and parts. The number "100" penciled in on cover.
  - Entre-act: Fantastiqué - Parts: Piano, March 15, 1875; 1.
  - Entre-act: Fantastiqué - Parts: Violin, March 15, 1875; 2.
  - Entre-act: Fantastiqué - Parts: Viola, March 15, 1875; 3.
  - Entre-act: Fantastiqué - Parts: Violoncello, March 15, 1875; 4.
- Barcarolle: in C Minor: for String Quartett, violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Barcarolle - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Barcarolle - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Barcarolle - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Barcarolle - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Cradlesong: in G Major: for String Quartett, violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 67, Folder 11)
  The number "7" pasted in on cover. The number "106" penciled in on cover.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Cradlesong - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Introductione et Scherzo: in G Minor: for String Quartett, violin 1 part (2 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 67, Folder 12)
  The number "8" pasted on cover. The number "107" penciled in on cover.
  - Introductione et Scherzo - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Introductione et Scherzo - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Introductione et Scherzo - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Introductione et Scherzo - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Valse Fantastique: [no.] 9: in A Major: for String Quartett, violin 1 part (2 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 67, Folder 13)
  The number "9" pasted in on cover. The number "108" penciled in on cover.
  - Valse Fantastique: [no.] 9 - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Valse Fantastique: [no.] 9 - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Valse Fantastique: [no.] 9 - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Valse Fantastique: [no.] 9 - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Serenade: for Trombone solo: with Orchestral Accompagnement: [in Ab major], March 23, 1893; 1 score (7 p.), flute part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), solo cornet or trombone part (1 p.), solo trombone part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), piano part (2 p.), violin 1 part (3 copies, 2,1,1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (1 p.), cello part (2 copies, each 1 p.), and bass (1 p.) (Box 68, Folder 1)
  Score in oblong format; parts for bassoon and bass trombone written in pencil throughout score. Parts are in 2 sizes: (27 cm and 35 cm [ms]). The smaller parts are published: Cincinnati: John Church Co., [n.d.]. On the verso of the published Zitterbart parts is the parts for The caress: morceau characteristic / Gaylord Barrett. Cover page has extremely brittle edges.
  - Serenade - Score, March 23, 1893; 1.
  - Serenade - Parts: Flute, March 23, 1893; 2.
  - Serenade - Parts: Clarinet 1, March 23, 1893; 3.
  - Serenade - Parts: Cornet 1, March 23, 1893; 4.
  - Serenade - Parts: Cornet 2, March 23, 1893; 5.
  - Serenade - Parts: Solo Cornet or Trombone, March 23, 1893; 6.
  - Serenade - Parts: Solo Trombone, March 23, 1893; 7.
  - Serenade - Parts: Trombone, March 23, 1893; 8.
  - Serenade - Parts: Piano, March 23, 1893; 9.
  - Serenade - Parts: Violin 1, March 23, 1893; 10.
  - Serenade - Parts: Violin 2, March 23, 1893; 11.
  - Serenade - Parts: Viola, March 23, 1893; 12.
  - Serenade - Parts: Violoncello, March 23, 1893; 13.
  - Serenade - Parts: Bass, March 23, 1893; 14.
- The Corporal's Song: [for] Trombone Solo [with] Piano accompagnement: [in Db major], 1 score (2 p.), and trombone part (1 p.) (Box 68, Folder 2)
  The number "30" penciled in on cover. The number "375" penciled in on cover.
  - The Corporal's Song - Score, 1.
  - The Corporal's Song - Parts: Trombone, 2.
- Amature Trio: for 2 Violins and Viola: [in C major], April 1, 1904; violin 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (5 p.), and viola part (5 p.) (Box 68, Folder 3)
  The number "559" penciled in on top-left of Viola part.
  - Amature Trio - Parts: Violin 1, April 1, 1904; 1.
  - Amature Trio - Parts: Violin 2, April 1, 1904; 2.
  - Amature Trio - Parts: Viola, April 1, 1904; 3.
- Spanish Serenade: for 2 Violins and Viola, December 29, 1892; violin 1 part (4 p.), violin 2 part (4 p.), and viola part (4 p.) (Box 68, Folder 4)
  The number "4" pasted in on cover. The number "560" penciled in on cover. Contents: 1. Spanish serenade -- 2. Indian tranquility -- 3. The fairys.
  - Spanish Serenade - Parts: Violin 1, December 29, 1892; 1.
  - Spanish Serenade - Parts: Violin 2, December 29, 1892; 2.
  - Spanish Serenade - Parts: Viola, December 29, 1892; 3.
- The Maid of Orleans: Characterstück: für Piano: [Op. 178: in Db major], 4 p. of music (Box 68, Folder 5)
  At head of title: Dedicated to my dear friend Frank. B. Weyman. On caption: "Schuldlos trieb ich meine Lämmer, auf des stillen Berges höh!"
- Ist dies der Tag des Herren: Symphonisch Bearbeitet für Orchester, Männerchor, Bass und Bariton solo, October 23, 1887; 1 score (21 p.), violin 1 part (4 p.), and violin 2 part (3 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 68, Folder 6)
  Incomplete. At head of title: Gedicht von Wilhelm Rothacker. Other instrumental parts lacking.
  - Ist dies der Tag des Herren - Score, October 23, 1887; 1.
  - Ist dies der Tag des Herren - Parts: Violin 1, October 23, 1887; 2.
  - Ist dies der Tag des Herren - Parts: Violin 2, October 23, 1887; 3.
  - Ist dies der Tag des Herren - Parts: Viola, October 23, 1887; 4.
- Poetic Suite: No. 5: in F Major: for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello, 1 score (14 p.), violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 68, Folder 7)
  Score is in oblong format and written in pencil. Written in pencil on t.p.: "with Bass ad lib for string orchestra." Texts of the poems each movement is based on stapled on verso of t.p. At head of Violin I part, "Please return (4 folders) to: Mr. A.E. Braun, Personal c/o Farmers Deposit National Bank, Pittsburgh, Pa." Contents: 1. April song -- 2. Shipwreck -- 3. An unknown guest -- 4. Anita -- 5. A Norse childs requiem -- 6. The naiad in winter.
  - Poetic Suite: No. 5 - Score, 1.
  - Poetic Suite: No. 5 - Violin 1, 2.
  - Poetic Suite: No. 5 - Violin 2, 3.
  - Poetic Suite: No. 5 - Viola, 4.
  - Poetic Suite: No. 5 - Violoncello, 5.
- The Christmas Tree: Morceau de Salon: for Violin, Violoncello and Piano, December 25, 1912; 1 score (6 p.), violin part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - The Christmas Tree - Score, December 25, 1912; 1.
  - The Christmas Tree - Parts: Violin, December 25, 1912; 2.
  - The Christmas Tree - Parts: Violoncello, December 25, 1912; 3.
- Blushes: Mazurka: for Orchestra: [in D major], flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), 2 horns part (2 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 68, Folder 9)
  An arrangement (?) of this piece which includes piano.
  - Blushes - Parts: Flute, 1.
  - Blushes - Parts: Oboe, 2.
  - Blushes - Parts: Clarinet 1, 3.
  - Blushes - Parts: Clarinet 2, 4.
  - Blushes - Parts: Bassoon, 5.
  - Blushes - Parts: Cornet 1, 6.
  - Blushes - Parts: Cornet 2, 7.
  - Blushes - Parts: Horns 1 and 2, 8.
  - Blushes - Parts: Trombone, 9.
  - Blushes - Parts: Drum, 10.
  - Blushes - Parts: Violin 1, 11.
  - Blushes - Parts: Violin 2, 12.
  - Blushes - Parts: Viola, 13.
  - Blushes - Parts: Violoncello, 14.
  - Blushes - Parts: Bass, 15.
  - Blushes - Parts: Piano, 16.
- No. I: Mazurka: Blushes: for Orchestra [and] No. II: Galop: Life on the Traction: for Orchestra, June 24, 1891; flute part (2 p.), oboe part (2 p.), clarinet part (2 p.), cornet part (2 p.), horn part (2 p.), trombone part (2 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 2 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 2 p.), viola part (2 p.), violoncello part (2 p.), and bass part (2 p.) (Box 68, Folder 10)
  The number "481" penciled in on cover.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Flute, June 24, 1891; 1.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Oboe, June 24, 1891; 2.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Clarinet, June 24, 1891; 3.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Cornet, June 24, 1891; 4.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Horn, June 24, 1891; 5.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Trombone, June 24, 1891; 6.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Violin 1, June 24, 1891; 7.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Violin 2, June 24, 1891; 8.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Viola, June 24, 1891; 9.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Violoncello, June 24, 1891; 10.
  - Mazurka - Parts: Bass, June 24, 1891; 11.
- Fernande: Polka-Mazurka: for Orchestra: [in G major], 1 score (7 p.), 2 flutes part (1 p.), oboe 1 part (1 p.), oboe 2 part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon 1 part (1 p.), bassoon 2 part (1 p.), trumpet 1 part (1 p.), trombone 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 part (1 p.), horn 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), timpani part (1 p.), triangle part (1 p.), violin 1 part (3 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (2 copies, each 1 p.), and bass part (2 copies, each 2 p.) (Box 68, Folder 11)
  Score in oblong format. "Opus 76" written in red ink on t.p. On parts: "Op. 54. No. 25." Location: New York.
  - Fernande - Score, 1.
  - Fernande - Parts: 2 Flutes, 2.
  - Fernande - Parts: Oboe 1, 3.
  - Fernande - Parts: Oboe 2, 4.
  - Fernande - Parts: Clarinet 1, 5.
  - Fernande - Parts: Clarinet 2, 6.
  - Fernande - Parts: Bassoon 1, 7.
  - Fernande - Parts: Bassoon 2, 8.
  - Fernande - Parts: Trumpet 1, 9.
  - Fernande - Parts: Trumpet 2, 10.
  - Fernande - Parts: Horn 1, 11.
  - Fernande - Parts: Horn 2, 12.
  - Fernande - Parts: Trombone, 13.
  - Fernande - Parts: Timpani, 14.
  - Fernande - Parts: Triangle, 15.
  - Fernande - Parts: Violin 1, 16.
  - Fernande - Parts: Violin 2, 17.
  - Fernande - Parts: Viola, 18.
  - Fernande - Parts: Violoncello, 19.
  - Fernande - Parts: Bass, 20.
- Pause and Reflect: Polka: for orchestra: [in A major], 1 score (8 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 in A part (1 p.), clarinet 2 in A part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 in A part (1 p.), cornet 2 in A part (1 p.), 2 horns part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum and triangle part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 68, Folder 12)
  Subtitle on score caption: Polka a la finesse.
  - Pause and Reflect - Score, 1.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Clarinet 1 in A, 4.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Clarinet 2 in A, 5.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Cornet 1 in A, 7.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Cornet 2 in A, 8.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: 2 Horns, 9.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Drum and Triangle, 11.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Bass, 16.
  - Pause and Reflect - Parts: Piano, 17.
- No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury: 2 Mazurkas: for orchestra, January 8, 1892; 2 scores (7 and 5 p.), flute part (2 p.), oboe part (2 p.), 2 clarinets part (2 p.), cornet in B part (2 p.), 2 horns part (2 p.), trombone part (2 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 2 p.)m violin 2 part (2 copies, each 2 p.), viola part (2 p.), violoncello part (2 p.), and bass part (2 p.) (Box 68, Folder 13)
  Scores in oblong format and written in pencil. Date of composition for Souvenier de Atterbury is 01/25/1892. Score for Souvenier de Atterbury has on caption: No. 7 (Einleitung zum Terzett)" and has 10 measures of music in pencil. Written over this in red and black ink is "No. 2. Souvenier de Atterbury."
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Scores 1 and 2, January 8, 1892; 1.
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Parts: Flute, January 8, 1892; 2.
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Parts: Oboe, January 8, 1892; 3.
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Parts: 2 Clarinets, January 8, 1892; 4.
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Parts: Cornet in B, January 8, 1892; 5.
  - No. 1: Kappler's Cello: [and] No. 2: Souvenir de Atterbury - Parts: Horn, January 8, 1892; 6.